# Nikema Prophet

An entry-level, language agnostic, software developer with over 20 years of experience as a technology enthusiast. My most recent focus is on frontend JavaScript development. I'm looking for my first technical position preferably in a community or people role. I am seeking remote positions, but I'm willing to relocate for the right opportunity. My preferred locations are SF/Bay Area, Sacramento, CA, New York, NY, and Atlanta, GA. Pronouns are: she/her/hers.

github.com/prophen https://nikema.dev nikema.prophet@popschools.com linkedin.com/in/nikemaprophet

# PROJECTS - <a href="https://nikema.dev/portfolio/">https://nikema.dev/portfolio/</a>

<u>Small Wins</u> — Built with Express.js, MongoDB, Svelte.js, and Twilio APIs

<u>A-Z Experiences</u> — Team project built with React.js and Semantic UI

<u>Empowered Conversations: Landing Page</u> — Built with HTML, CSS/Less, JavaScript as a contribution to the team project

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **PopSchools, Inc.,** Sacramento, CA — Founder/CEO

OCTOBER 2017 - PRESENT

- PopSchools provides a suite of products and services to allow for flexible work & living for tech-enabled families.
- Created branding and built a web presence, including social media and email list

## **Code for Hood**, Sacramento, CA — *Instructor*

APRIL 2019 - MAY 2019

- Taught teens in a summer session about personal branding, content creation, and entrepreneurship.
- Responsible for lesson plans, classroom management, and submitting invoices for payment

## **Code for Hood**, Sacramento, CA — *Instructor*

FALL 2017

- Created and facilitated an 8-week course on entrepreneurship.
- Was responsible for twice weekly classes, creating and submitting lesson plans, and attending team meetings.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Tools

Visual Studio Code, Vim, Git

## Database Management

Relational Databases, SQL, MongoDB, MySQL, MS Access

# Languages/Frameworks

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Swift, React.js

# Web Servers/Serverless Deployment

Deploying applications to Netlify, Heroku, ZEIT, Firebase, Google Cloud, Cloud

## **EDUCATION**

# <u>Lambda School</u> -Summer Hackers Program

May 2019 - August 2019 Completed Coursework Includes:

- User Interface and Git
- Advanced CSS
- JavaScript Fundamentals
- Applied JavaScript
- React
- Single Page Applications

# <u>Sacramento City College</u> Sacramento, CA — *Web Developer Certificate*

2007 - 2012

Completed Coursework Includes:

- Database Programming
- Designing Accessible Websites
- Middleware Web Scripting
- Object Oriented Programming JAVA